Guide to the Collège de la Sainte Famille Collection AD.MC.028
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
College de la Sainte Famille Collection
1880 - 1990
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.028
6 paige_boxes - 1,402 photographs, digital surrogates only retained by Akkasah: Center for Photography.
The images in this collection document the history of the Collège de la Sainte Famille in Cairo, Egypt. CSF was founded in 1887 by Casimiro Giacomelli, a priest of the Comboni Missionaries to serve the local population of Helwan (25km south of central Cairo) – Egyptian and foreign, Christian and Muslim. The photographs focus on the staff and students of CSF. The majority are taken during school events and a number during excursions. The first staff portrait dates from 1894. There is also a series of architecture focussed images.
Object AD_MC_028 Digital surrogates only
Biographical / Historical
The Collège Sainte Famille (CSF) was founded in 1887 by Casimiro Giacomelli, a priest of the Comboni Missionaries who had previously been posted in Sudan. CSF was a private initiative to serve the local population of Helwan (25km south of central Cairo) – Egyptian and foreign, Christian and Muslim. At the time of its founding, Egypt had a fledgling public education system and several churches established schools with official endorsement. Known today as the Holy Family School, it remains Helwan's oldest and most distinguished school. It has evolved from being an entirely European initiative to being an Egyptian school in all respects. Its administrators, teachers, and pupils hail largely from the local neighborhood, although a few dozen students travel from across the Nile or adjacent neighborhoods to the north. CSF-Helwan carries on as a private institution administered by the Comboni Missionaries.
Arrangement
Collection processed in the order in which it was received.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired directly from College de la Sainte Famille.
Scope and Contents
The photographs, which span from the 1890s to the 1990s, focus on the staff and students of the Collège Sainte Famille. The majority are taken during school events - sports days, parades, musical performances and awards ceremonies - and a number during excursions - places visited include Suez, Giza, Saqqara, Alexandria, Fayoum, Mit Rahina, Helwan Observatory, Capritage hot springs, Ezbet El-Walda archaeological site and the Japanese Garden in Helwan (constructed in 1917). The first staff portrait dates from 1894.
There is also a series of architecture focussed images, which document doorways and entrances around Helwan, the school building, surrounding churches, mosques and villas.
Helwan, Egypt; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Students; Teachers; Japanese Garden, Helwan, Egypt; Priests/Clergymen; Nuns
- School portrait with young boys. 12.4 x 16.7 cm, Circa 1900 (Object AD_MC_028_ref1)
  Helwan, Egypt; Students; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Schools/Education; Boys; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Children; Italian Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints
- School portrait with teachers including Catholic clergymen. 11.6 x 18 cm, 1903 (Object AD_MC_028_ref2)
  Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Students; Teachers; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Religious Crosses; Ceremonies; Boys; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Uniforms; Facial Hair; Men; Children
- Three children in the Japanese Gardens. 13.3 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref3)
  Costumes; Gardens; French Writing; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Girls; Boys; Japanese Garden, Helwan, Egypt; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Water; Students
- Eva Laurella in her car. 8.3 x 13.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref4)
  Houses; Women; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Cars/Trucks; Helwan, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Transportation
- Eva Laurella's car, a Fiat 508B Balilla. 8 x 11 cm, Circa 1934-1937 (Object AD_MC_028_ref5)
  Jewelry; Streets/Roads; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Women; Cars/Trucks; Helwan, Egypt; Transportation; Group Portraits; Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Group portrait of school staff with friar Modesto. 11.5 x 17.6 cm, Circa 1915 (Object AD_MC_028_ref6)
  Group Portraits; Medals/Insignia; Teachers; Fez/Tarboush; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Priests/Clergymen; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Hats; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Helwan, Egypt; Men
- Students on a field trip to the White Desert (Farafra). 14.4 x 9.3 cm, 1951 (Object AD_MC_028_ref7)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Boys; Deserts; Group Portraits; Students; Schools/Education; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Children
- Students on a field trip with Father Varatto. 8.6 x 13.7 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref8)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Deserts; Boys; Students; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Palm Trees; Hats; Children; Men; Facial Hair
- Boys' gymnastics class with Father Rodrigo. 9.1 x 13.8 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref9)
  Students; Italian Writing; Children; Outdoors; Sports; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Boys; Schools/Education; Group Portraits
- School portrait of students and Father Giacomelli. 12.7 x 17.8 cm, Circa 1900 (Object AD_MC_028_ref10)
  Children; Facial Hair; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Teachers; Students; Boys; Group Portraits; Schools/Education; Facial Hair; Hats; Priests/Clergymen; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men
- School portrait. 14.3 x 11.1 cm, Circa 1900 (Object AD_MC_028_ref11)
  Italian Writing; Children; Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Hats; Schools/Education; Students; Group Portraits
- Boys' gymnastics class in the school courtyard held by Father Rodrigo. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref12)
  Group Portraits; Children; Boys; Students; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Sports; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Two nuns with students at the beach in Alexandria, Egypt. 9 x 9.9 cm, Circa 1940-1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref13)
  Nuns; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Schools/Education; Children; Alexandria, Egypt; Beaches; Group Portraits; Students; Girls; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Boys' gymnastics class with Father Rodrigo. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref14)
  Sports; Helwan, Egypt; Children; Boys; Students; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men
- Boys carrying watermelons in Wallis Resort, Suez. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref15)
  Suez, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Schools/Education; Boys; Group Portraits; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Children; Palm Trees; Food; Men
- Staff of the Evergreen Hotel being photographed by Laurella. 6.4 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref16)
  Men; Hats; Helwan, Egypt; Cameras; Hotels; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Workers
- Laurella's car (a Fiat Balilla) on the road close to the pyramids. 6 x 8.6 cm, Circa 1934 (Object AD_MC_028_ref17)
  Women; Helwan, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Transportation
- School trip to the pyramids. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref18)
  Children; Boys; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Hats; Uniforms; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt
- Four boys posing in theatrical costumes with guns in the school theater. 12.3 x 17 cm, Circa 1910 (Object AD_MC_028_ref19)
  Weapons; Children; Schools/Education; Boys; Costumes; Theater; Guns; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Painted Backdrops; Performance Plays; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Four boys posing in theatrical costumes in the school theater. 12.3 x 17.3 cm, Circa 1910 (Object AD_MC_028_ref20)
  Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Canes/Walking Sticks; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Helwan, Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Theater; Costumes; Boys; Performance Plays; Schools/Education
- School dormitory. 12.4 x 16.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref21)
  Helwan, Egypt; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Furnishings
- Two trucks parked on 55 Moustafa Fahmi Street. 12.9 x 12.8 cm, 1984 (Object AD_MC_028_ref22)
  Helwan, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Architecture; Schools/Education; Arabic Writing; Streets/Roads; Italian Writing; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Houses; Transportation; Gelatin Silver Prints
- School portrait with young boys and four teachers in gardens. 13.1 x 18 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref23)
  Outdoors; Helwan, Egypt; Parks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Teachers; Students; Boys; Palm Trees; Schools/Education; Outdoors; Group Portraits
- Group portrait of the school staff in a garden with Father Milan. 11.8 x 18 cm, 1930 (Object AD_MC_028_ref24)
  Arabic Writing; Priests/Clergymen; Italian Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Hats; Teachers; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Regional/National Dress; Gardens; Schools/Education; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Turbans; Outdoors; Facial Hair; Men
- King Fuad I of Egypt signing an official document in Helwan. 17.8 x 13.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref25)
  Signatures; Medals/Insignia; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Pens/Inkwells; Ceremonies; Fez/Tarboush; Officials; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Men; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Royalty; Hats; Fuad I, King of Egypt, 1868-1936
- Children sitting at a table outside and peeling vegetables. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref26)
  Photographic Prints; Suez, Egypt; Group Portraits; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Bicycles/Tricycles; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Boys; Children
- Helwan Wax Museum exhibit of a man reciting from the Qur'an. 12.6 x 8.9 cm, 1984 (Object AD_MC_028_ref27)
  Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Quran/Koran; Statues/Sculptures; Museums; Arabic Calligraphy; Color Photography
- King Fuad I of Egypt in front of the Physical Department of the Meteorological Station. 17.9 x 13.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref28)
  Photographic Prints; Men; Parades/Processions; Fez/Tarboush; Canes/Walking Sticks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Uniforms; Italian Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Officials; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Fuad I, King of Egypt, 1868-1936
- Group portrait with Father Cremono at Suez Canal in front of a boat. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref29)
  Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boys; Boats/Ships; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Flags; Italian Writing; Canals; Arabic Writing; Suez, Egypt; Group Portraits; Rivers; Priests/Clergymen; Helwan, Egypt
- A group of boys standing by the Colossus of King Ramses II in Memphis, Egypt. Taken by Father Cremono. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref30)
  Children; Helwan, Egypt; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Photographic Prints; Memphis, Egypt; Group Portraits; Students; Gelatin Silver Prints; Statues/Sculptures; Boys; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Museums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Schools/Education
- Man sitting at Wadi Hof in the Helwan desert. 12.3 x 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref31)
  Deserts; Photographic Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Wadi Hof, Helwan, Egypt; Men
- Photograph of a Scout Leader; Sabry with Father Aletto in the palm area. 8.9 x 13.6 cm, 1949-1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref32)
  Scouts; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Priests/Clergymen; Palm Trees; Men; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Hats
- Men and Women dining at the Evergreen Hotel. 7 x 10.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref33)
  Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Food; Gatherings; Women; Helwan, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Hotels; Waiting staff/Servers; Drinks/Beverages; Head Covers/Veils
- Students on a field trip to Fayoum, posing in front of a bus. 9.2 x 14.4 cm, 1955 (Object AD_MC_028_ref34)
  Boys; Buses; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Schools/Education; Students; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Fayoum, Egypt; Facial Hair; Helwan, Egypt; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Hats; Teachers; Transportation; Men
- Three children sitting with Doctor Ghanz outside on 26 Sherif Street. 13.9 x 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref35)
  Helwan, Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gardens; Palm Trees; Outdoors; Doctors; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Streets/Roads; Facial Hair; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Group Portraits
- Group portrait of boys at Suez Resort, two hold fishing nets. 13 x 13.1 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref36)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Fishing; Hats; Group Portraits; Pottery; Suez, Egypt; Children; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt
- Boys sitting around a dining table in Suez. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref37)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Suez, Egypt; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Helwan, Egypt; Boys; Food; Students
- Street view of 39 Heidar Pacha Street. 10.7 x 13.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref38)
  Helwan, Egypt; Architecture; Outdoors; Houses; Streets/Roads; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing
- Villa and garden of Dr. Ghanz on 26 Sherif Street. 12.9 x 12.9 cm, Undated. (Object AD_MC_028_ref39)
  Palm Trees; Outdoors; Gardens; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Buildings
- Helwan school banner. 13.8 x 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref40)
  Ceremonies; Boys; Helwan, Egypt; Schools/Education; Flags; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Medals/Insignia; Children; Individual Portraits
- Students on a boat with professor Martini on the Nile. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref41)
  Schools/Education; Teachers; Children; Boys; Students; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Rivers; Palm Trees; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A man wearing a uniform standing on the shore of the Suez canal. 13.9 x 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref42)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Police; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Uniforms; Suez, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Coast; Helwan, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing
- Students on a field trip standing with Father Cremono. 9.3 x 14.4 cm, 1952 (Object AD_MC_028_ref43)
  Boys; Students; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Children; Italian Writing; Group Portraits; Hats; Helwan, Egypt; Teachers; Bridges; Priests/Clergymen; Schools/Education; Men
- School portrait with a clergyman. 9 x 12.1 cm, Circa 1895 (Object AD_MC_028_ref44)
  Italian Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Students; Schools/Education; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Arabic Writing
- Students and teachers posing on top of a tower in Suez. 14.2 x 9.3 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref45)
  Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Priests/Clergymen; Boys; Students; Teachers; Schools/Education
- The Caude Refractor at the Helwan Observatory. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1902 (Object AD_MC_028_ref46)
  Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Observatories; Telescope; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints
- Teachers and students in paddle boats. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref47)
  Group Portraits; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students; Helwan, Egypt; Lakes; Boys; Teachers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Ponds; Boats/Ships; Children; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- School dormitory. 9 x 14 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref48)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Furnishings
- Students posing in the desert during a school field trip. 14.5 x 9.7 cm, 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref49)
  Students; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Children; Arabic Writing; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Boys
- Students at the Japanese Garden. 9 x 13.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref50)
  Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Students; Boys; Schools/Education; Teachers; Men; Japanese Garden, Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Statues/Sculptures; Helwan, Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Buddha statues in the Japanese Garden. 9 x 13.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref51)
  Palm Trees; Water; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Ponds; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Japanese Garden, Helwan, Egypt; Helwan, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Gardens; Landscapes; Bridges
- Father Cremono with men next to palm trees. 9 x 13.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref52)
  Palm Trees; Camels; Animals; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Men; Helwan, Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Group Portraits; Deserts; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Turbans
- A shepherdess posing in front of goats during a field trip to Helwan El-Balad. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1952 (Object AD_MC_028_ref53)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals; Women; Goats; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Canes/Walking Sticks; Countryside/Rural; Boys; Shepherds; Children
- Students during a school trip on a felucca. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref54)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Helwan, Egypt; Boys; Water; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Students; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Nile River; Group Portraits; Schools/Education
- Group portrait of boy scouts. 14 x 6.4 cm, 1980 (Object AD_MC_028_ref55)
  Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Students; Children; Teachers; Boys; Men; Schools/Education; Uniforms; Banners; Hats; Scouts; Helwan, Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
- Eva Laurella posing on a horse with another woman. 10.2 x 8.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref56)
  Women; Horses; Animals; Photographic Prints; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Men; Helwan, Egypt
- Portrait of Muhammed Tewfik Pasha I. 13.8 X 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref57)
  Arabic Writing; Royalty; Officials; Helwan, Egypt; Men; Postcards; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Pasha; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Facial Hair; Hats; Postcards; Medals/Insignia; Tawfīq Pasha, Mohamed, Khedive of Egypt, 1852-1892
- Postcard of Khedive Ismail Pasha. 13.9 x 9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref58)
  Helwan, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Officials; Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Royalty; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Pasha; Postcards; Facial Hair; Hats; Ismail, Pasha, Khedive of Egypt, 1830-1895
- Students in a classroom taken by Father Cremono. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1940 (Object AD_MC_028_ref59)
  Schools/Education; Students; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Boys; Helwan, Egypt
- Students acting in a school play. 9.3 x 12.8 cm, 1954 (Object AD_MC_028_ref60)
  Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Helwan, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Performance Plays; Children; Actors; Men; Hats; Costumes; Theater; Boys; Students; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints
- Alumni in costume at school theatre. 9 x 13.9 cm, 1910 (Object AD_MC_028_ref61)
  Armor; Actors; Armor; Armor; Actors; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Men; Performance Plays; Theater; Costumes; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Spears; Weapons; Painted Backdrops; Group Portraits
- Restaurant of the Evergreen Hotel. 8.6 x 13.1 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref62)
  Hotels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Restaurants/bars; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Helwan, Egypt; Hats
- Students performing in a play. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref63)
  Actors; Actors; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Students; Boys; Theater; Performance Plays; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Schools/Education; Furnishings; Helwan, Egypt; Costumes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Hats
- Students and man in costume for school play. 9.3 x 12.1 cm, 1954 (Object AD_MC_028_ref64)
  Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Actors; Children; Actors; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Theater; Costumes; Boys; Men; Hats; Facial Hair
- Giordino Giopponese. Group posing in the Japanese Garden. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_028_ref65)
  Statues/Sculptures; Women; Men; Gardens; Japanese Garden, Helwan, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Helwan, Egypt; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Jewelry
- Student playing the trumpet with Father Aletto. 13.8 x 9 cm, 1949-1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref66)
  Schools/Education; Helwan, Egypt; Students; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Brass Instruments; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Priests/Clergymen; Men; Brass Instruments; Children; Group Portraits
- Group portrait of school staff. 9 x 13.2 cm, 1962-1963 (Object AD_MC_028_ref67)
  Priests/Clergymen; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Teachers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Schools/Education; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- Students at a sports event playing tug of war. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Circa 1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref68)
  Crowds; Helwan, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Students; Boys; Sports; Audiences/Spectators; Buildings; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Children; Group Portraits
- Two buses on the road for a school field trip to Fayoum, Egypt. 8.6 x 13.5 cm, 1955 (Object AD_MC_028_ref69)
  Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fayoum, Egypt; Helwan, Egypt; Egypt; Streets/Roads; Boys; Schools/Education; Students; Transportation; Buses; Photographic Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing
- Two boys standing with their arm outstretched. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1940-1950 (Object AD_MC_028_ref70)
  Boys; Students; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Italian Writing; Arabic Writing; Costumes; Children; Schools/Education; Buildings; Helwan, Egypt; Uniforms; Group Portraits